星际之门之亚特兰蒂斯 前情提要
Previously, on Stargate Atlantis...
我们对幽灵知道些多少？
What do we know about the Wraith?
所知不多  其中之一就是它们是打败古人的敌人
One of the few things we do know is that
they are the enemy that defeated the ancients.
有时 几百年后它们才会再次醒来
Sometimes, a few hundred years
will pass before they awaken again.
我们已经到过很多很多星球了
We have visited many, many worlds.
据有所知 没有哪个没有被幽灵所蹂躏的
I know of none untouched by the Wraith.
你们注定是会灭亡的
就跟许多与你们同路的人类一样
You are doomed, as are any
humans that stand in our way.
古人曾经研究过"升天"
The ancients were researching ascension.
"升天"到底是什么意思?
What exactly is ascension?
一个他们所能够达到的更高级的阶段
An advanced stage of being where they were able
让他们摆脱自己的肉身
to rid themselves of their physical bodies
上升到一个更高的存在形式
and rise to a higher plane of existence,
最终他们纯粹以能量形式生存
one in which they live as pure energy.
- 我数到二, 准备好了么?
- 是的, 长官
- I count two. How about you?
- Yes, sir.
- 我建议现在立刻进行回击
- 我正在努力
- I recommend shooting back any time now.
- I'm trying.
- 刚才的一击一定造成了一些损坏. McKay?
- 我就去看看
- That hit must've caused some damage. McKay?
- I'm on it.
它们是从哪里来的?
Where did they come from?
她是对的  那些看似飞标的物体正是短程战斗机
She's right. The darts are short-range fighters.
这附近一定有一艘母船
There's probably a hive ship around here somewhere.
- 那么我们应该马上离开这里
- 是的
- Then we need to get out of here.
- Yes, we do.
星际之门在另外一边
行星的另一侧
The Stargate's the other way,
on the other side of the planet.
是, 我们现在简直就像是在观光漫步  McKay!
Yeah, we're taking the scenic route. McKay!
我就快搞定了!
I've almost there!
有一个正在我们身后!
There's one on our tail!
谢谢, 我也知道
把你的眼睛用来盯住另外那个
Thank you, I know all about that one.
Keep your eye on the other one.
OK, 你应该可以用武器了
Okay, you should have weapons now.
- 不行
- 你确信?
- Negative.
- Are you sure?
- 肯定
- 我非常肯定我已经把它修好了
- Positive!
- I'm pretty sure I fixed it.
好吧, 实际上你根本就没有!
Well, obviously you didn't!
也许你可以在大气层中把它们甩掉
Perhaps you can lose them in
the atmosphere of the planet.
两点钟方向又来了两艘
Two more darts on our two o'clock.
我看到了. McKay!
I see them. McKay!
我看起来可不是正在故意妨碍你
It's not like I'm holding back on you.
抓好!
Hang on!
幽灵的梭镖飞船已经被消灭了
The Wraith darts have been destroyed.
好, 这是件好事
Well, that's a good thing.
我敢肯定我们已经死了
你们认为我们现在死了么
I thought for sure we were dead.
Didn't you think we were dead?
那到底是什么?
What the hell was that?
某种, 嗯, 能量武器?
Some sort of, uh, energy weapon?
你说我们发现了什么?
What do you say we find out?
星际之门之亚特兰蒂斯
第一季第14集 避难所
Season 1: Episode 14 Sanctuary
那么, 肯定一下, 我们仍然...
So just to confirm, we're all still...
明确的说还没有死
definitely not dead.
我感觉活得很好
I feel very much alive.
很好  我也一样
Good. Same here.
我很想知道那到底是什么
I wish I knew what that was.
看起来像闪电
Looked like lightning.
太空闪电?
Space lightning?
我已经说了, 那是某种能量武器
显然是它摧毁了幽灵的飞船
I already said, it's some sort of an energy weapon,
one that apparently destroys Wraith darts.
不错, 但为什么摧毁的只是它们而不是我们?
Nice, but why them and not us?
好吧, 假设我们仍然还活着
而且也没有任何损坏
Well, assuming that we're still alive,
and there doesn't appear to be any damage
从脉搏的结果来看
我想我们可以确实的得出结论, 嗯...
as a result of the pulse,
I think we can safely conclude that, uh...
我什么也没有得到
I got nothing.
我的意思是, 我没有得到什么结论
I mean, I got nothing to conclude.
我只是为了说话而说话
I'm just talking for the sake of talking.
你确信你还好吧?
Are you sure you're okay?
你知道我是多么憎恶死亡?
You know how much I hate certain death?
你还活着
You're alive.
这会是某种自然现象么?
Could something like that be naturally occurring?
肯定不是
My money's on non-naturally occurring.
有没可能是古人留下的武器?
Like a weapon the ancients left behind?
任何有如此威力的武器
的能量来源一定是...
And any weapon that impressive
would have to be powered by...
- ... 零点模块
- 对
- ... a zero-point module.
- That's right.
好吧, 我们需要下去
All right, we need to get down there.
不管怎么说, 在我们返回亚特兰蒂斯之前
需要检查一下有没有什么损坏
I've got to check for damage anyway
before we head back to Atlantis.
如果下面某个地方确实有这种武器
长官, 那也肯定不是这些家伙造的
If there is a weapon somewhere down here,
sir, these folks didn't build it.
不是这些孩子们
Not these kids.
你发现什么了么?
You picking up anything?
我正在检查一切
没有什么值得关注的
I'm picking up everything,
just nothing worth mentioning.
这些人看起来跟你比较亲近, Teyla?
These folks look familiar to you, Teyla?
星际之门是在轨道中, 少校
我的人们不可能探险来到这里
The Stargate is in orbit, Major.
My people could never have ventured here.
对
那我们去探险如何?
Right.
What say we venture?
嗨
Hi.
没事. 我们很友好
It's okay. We're friendly.
嗨
Hi.
看起来他们好像没有见过村子外的人.
It is likely they have never seen
anyone from outside their village.
欢迎
Welcome.
我叫Zarah, Proculis的一个修道士
I am Zarah, one of the abbots of Proculis.
我是John. John Sheppard.
I'm John. John Sheppard.
这是Teyla, Ford中尉, 以及McKay博士
This is Teyla, lieutenant Ford, and dr. McKay.
请, 来吧
Please, come.
这是我生命中第一次看到
其他国家的人来到我们这里
This is the first time at least in my own lifetime
that people from another land have come to us.
嗯, 我们是坐飞船来的
Well, we came by ship.
一个可以飞的东西
可以把我们从一个星球带到另外一个星球
A flying thing that allows us
to move from one world to another.
另一个星球?
Another world?
从你们夜晚看到的星星中间
From among the stars you see in the night sky.
我们是和平的探险者
We are peaceful explorers.
那么感谢Athar把你们安全的带到这里
Then glory to Athar for bringing you here safely.
Athar?
我们所有人的供应者... 和保护者
The provider... and protector of all.
你们应该知道
Surely you know.
Athar是我们所知诸多星辰中的一个
Athar is known by many names among the stars.
嗯... Athar在周围么?
Is, um... Athar around?
我们很想跟他谈谈.
我们是, 嗯, 朋友
We'd love to talk to him.
We're, uh, friends.
Athar是我们所有人的朋友, 而且他永远和我们在一起
Athar is friend to all, and with us always.
即使是现在
Even now.
当然
Of course.
嗨, Athar.
Hi, Athar.
McKay博士的意思是
我们想表达我们的谢意
What dr. McKay means is that
we wish to offer our thanks.
我们被幽灵袭击
We were attacked by the Wraith
and would have been killed,
如果不是Athar的干涉
我们几乎就被它们杀死了
were it not for Athar's intervention.
"幽灵"?
"Wraith"?
苍白的皮肤, 深陷的眼睛
用手将你的生命吸取出来
Pale skin, sunken eyes,
suck the life out of you with their hands?
我们从来没有碰到过这种事情
We have never encountered such beings.
从来?
Never?
而且你们的历史中也从来没有提及?
And there is no mention of them in your history?
没有
None.
我可以向你保证, 几千年来
我们都生活在和平之中
I can assure you that for many thousands of years,
we have lived here in peace.
能让我们离开一会儿么?
Could you excuse us for a moment?
当然. 不过不是现在  在我们会见Chaya之前
我要告诉其他的修道士你们的到来
Of course. Please, I must tell the other abbots
of your arrival before we go to meet with Chaya.
那么Chaya又是...
And Chaya is...
Athar的女祭司
The high priestess of Athar.
这对我们人民来说是伟大的一天
This is a great day for our people.
对我们也是
Ours too.
不是开玩笑
这真的有作用?
I'm not kidding. This could really work.
我同意, 少校
I agree, Major.
在这个星系中, 所有我访问过的星球
都曾经遭受过幽灵的蹂躏
Every inhabited world I have encountered
in this galaxy has been ravaged by the Wraith.
嗯, 这个星球受到了古人的武器的保护
Well, this planet is protected
by an Ancient weapon.
这正好可以肯定这一点
This just confirms it.
是么?
Does it?
好吧, 没有第二种解释了
Well, there's no other explanation.
我的意思是, 那种东西对能量的需求
是相当惊人的
I mean, the power requirements of
something like that must be astronomical.
只有 Z.P.M. 可以产生那种能量
Only a Z.P.M. could generate that.
而且现在...在技术上
他们还没有发达到那种地步
And yet... they do not appear
to be technologically advanced.
除非刚才那个家伙在撒谎
但他不像是会撒谎的那种人
Unless that guy was lying,
but he doesn't seem like the lying type.
那么, 自动防御?
So, automated defenses.
想象一下, 有这样一个星球
可以把其他星球上的难民转移过来, 和平的生活
Imagine a world where displaced refugees from
dozens of planets could come and live in peace,
不用再担心会被幽灵抓去
without fear of being culled by the Wraith.
也许我们可以跟他们谈判
Maybe we can negotiate some kind of treaty.
最好我们能被允许使用那个武器, 那个Z.P.M.
We just need access to that
weapon better still, the Z.P.M.,
实在不行我们就去偷了它
not that we'd steal it or anything.
我们应该尽量光明正大一点
Let's just try to stay on our best behavior.
我总是光明正大的
I'm always on my best behavior.
有多远?
How much farther?
不是很远
Not very.
噢, 很好
Oh, good.
瞧? 我们本可以坐飞船去的
See? We could have taken the jumper.
对你来说, 锻炼一下不是坏事
The exercise is good for you.
Chaya住得离你的人民确实远了点
Chaya does live pretty far from your people.
这很不寻常, 少校
牧师竟然不是住在社区当中
It is not uncommon, Major,
for clerics to live apart from the community.
以伟大Athar的名义
Glory to Athar.
欢迎, 请就便
Welcome, and rest.
谢谢你, 女教士
Thank you, sister.
对Proculis来说,  你们都是新人
You are new to Proculis.
是的,  我们...
Yes. We're, uh...
我们是"崭新的", 事实上
we're brand new, in fact.
John Sheppard少校
Major John Sheppard.
我的名字叫Chaya Sar.
I am called Chaya Sar.
那么你是...
And you are...
Teyla...
Ford中尉, 以及McKay博士
Lieutenant Ford, and Dr. McKay.
她是怎么知道的?
How did she know that?
噢, 这都不懂
Oh, please.
有个修道士先来过了
One of the abbots ran ahead.
很高兴见到你, Chaya.
It's a pleasure to meet you, Chaya.
走了这么远, 你们一定累了吧
You must be tired after your long journey.
我可以去准备些茶么?
Shall I prepare some tea for us?
我想我们也正想这么说
I was hoping you were going to say just that.
那么那些幽灵是从哪里来的?
And where do they come from, these Wraith?
看起来它们在这个星系中无处不在
They seem to be everywhere in this galaxy,
and they appear to have been on top
而且看起来在很长一段时间内
它们处于食物链的顶端
of the food chain for a long time.
这太恐怖了
It's terrifying.
确实很恐怖
Truly terrifying.
我非常为你的人民担心, Teyla.
My heart goes out to your people, Teyla.
遭受厄运的不仅仅只是我的人民, Chaya.
It is not only my people who suffer, Chaya.
幽灵已经从长时间的睡眠中苏醒过来了
The Wraith have awakened from a long sleep,
不过在已经开始的选择中(指幽灵选择食物)
这整个星球看起来却是安全的
and this entire world is safe from
the culling that has already begun.
即便是亚特兰蒂斯, 即使有那么多的奇迹
也可能经受不住冲击
Even Atlantis, with all its wonder,
may not survive the onslaught.
我们共同希望Athar
允许在Proculis, 也就是在这里, 建立避难所
It is our hope that Athar
could grant sanctuary here on Proculis.
避难所?
Sanctuary?
为如此之多的人?
For so many?
嗯, 我们并不是说这个星系中所有的人
都会出现在你的门口
Well, we're not talking about everybody
in the galaxy showing up on your doorstep.
这个行星很大, 女士
This planet is pretty big, ma'am.
而且大部分无人居住
And it is largely uninhabited.
更重要的是
它受到你们那种武器的保护
More importantly,
it is protected by that weapon of yours.
武器?
Weapon?
我想在Proculis没有这种东西
I am aware of no such thing on Proculis.
你确信?
Are you sure about that?
是的
Yes.
噢, 不要这样
Oh, please.
Rodney, 表现好一点
Rodney, best behavior.
这跟我们得到的已经是一样好了, 少校
This is as good as it gets, Major.
Chaya, 我们还活着的唯一原因就是
Chaya, the only reason we're alive
is because of a powerful energy weapon
从这个星球表面某处发射出来的
某种强大的能量武器
that emanated from somewhere
on the surface of this planet.
它摧毁了朝我们射击的飞船
It destroyed the ships that were shooting at us.
正是那个武器使幽灵无法靠近
That weapon is what's keeping the Wraith away.
不,  McKay博士
No, Dr. McKay.
是Athar保护了你们
It was Athar who protected you.
Athar?
是的
Yes.
Athar看到你们需要他
Athar saw you were in need.
Chaya, 有非常多的人就像...
Chaya, there are a lot of people just like...
你和我, 都需要他, 因为幽灵
you and me, who are in need because of the Wraith.
你们在这里所拥有的,  也就是Athar提供给你们的
是非常稀有的东西...
What you have here, what Athar
has provided you, is a very rare thing...
不过我们需要把他也提供给更多的人
but we have a lot to offer too.
这就是朋友所应该做的
他们共同分享
That's what friends do. They share.
我想我们可以互相帮助
I think we could help each other.
我知道了
I understand.
我现在应该和她商量一下
I shall consult with her now.
请待在这里
我不知道这需要多长时间
Please stay here.
I don't know how long this will take.
谢谢
Thank you.
"Athar提供给你们的?"
"What Athar provides for you?"
你也想承认这些?
You're buying into this?
Rodney...
这些虔诚的人们怎么可能
不认真对待他们自己的宗教?
what religious people don't
take their religion seriously?
那个武器并不是我们想象出来的, 少校
We didn't imagine that weapon, Major.
我们亲眼看见了
而且我们也看见了它的能力
We saw it with our own eyes,
and we saw what it was capable of.
是的, 我们确实看见了
Yes, we did.
也许Chaya只是不知道那个武器的存在
Perhaps Chaya is simply
unaware of the weapon's existence.
或许她知道, 不过她不想让我们也知道
Or she knows, and she wants
to keep it a secret from us.
从她对我说话的语气来看
也不像是在说谎
She doesn't strike me
as the lying type either.
好吧, 我们就看看Athar会说些什么
All right, let's just see
what Athar has to say.
就是说, "别管幕后那人是怎么说的", 是么?
So, "pay no attention to
the man behind the curtain," hmm?
很对
Exactly.
少校
Major.
我们已经向我们神圣的母亲
传达了你的请求
We have conveyed your
request to our divine mother,
虽然她并没有怀疑你们行动的正义性,
and although she does not doubt
the righteousness of your mission,
我恐怕还是要说, 她不会允许
除了她的子民之外的其他人居住在这里
I'm afraid she cannot countenance
any other people but hers settling here.
你真的需要总是"唱"得这么好听么?
And you really had to chant
all that time to come up with that?
McKay.
我们有没有办法请求Athar重新考虑一下?
Is there any way we can
ask Athar to reconsider?
Athar 理解且也很认同
那些幽灵是我们星球当中的灾难
Athar understands and sympathizes
these Wraith are a scourge among our stars
不过她必须把她自己人民的生命放在第一位
but she has to place the
lives of her people first.
好吧, 我想我们在来这里很久之前
Well, I think we both knew
what you were going to say
就已经都知道了你准备说的了
long before you even went in there.
我们祈求Athar的指引
We prayed for Athar's guidance.
那么Athar是怎么说的?
And what did Athar say?
你们藏在你们所谓的信仰背后
来证明你们完完全全的自私自利
You're hiding behind your religion to
justify your complete and utter selfishness.
Rodney...
如果 Athar 确实存在, 她自己也会觉得羞愧
if Athar existed, she
would be ashamed of herself.
我们只是请求不被打扰, 平静的生活下去
We ask only to be left alone and in peace.
所有数不清的成千上万的, 甚至上百万的
人就应该死去
So untold thousands, possibly millions
of people will die out there
在他们可以被一个叫做Athar的人拯救的时候
when they could have been saved,
all in the name of Athar.
你们可真, 真是平静啊
How very, very peaceful of you.
你应该感激 Athar.
You should be grateful to Athar.
这是在浪费时间
This is a waste of time.
Athar 很抱歉她不能帮助你们
Athar regrets that she cannot help you.
而且我相信这就是她的原话
And I'm sure those were her exact words.
够了
That's enough.
回到飞船那里去
Head back to the jumper.
我过会就来
I'll be there in a minute.
为什么?
Why?
因为你毫无帮助
Because you're not helping.
是的, 长官
Yes, sir.
我很抱歉
I apologize.
他只是心直口快, 我们也是
He acts only in accordance
to his beliefs, as do we.
不过 Rodney 说的没错
But Rodney is right about one thing.
这事关生命,  人类的生命
This really is about lives, human lives.
迟早, 幽灵会出现在亚特兰蒂斯
到那时...
Sooner or later, the Wraith are going to
show up at Atlantis, and when they do...
你是个武士
you're a warrior.
嗯, 我并不了解 "武士"
Well, I don't know about "warrior."
这是你的职业, 少校
It is your vocation, Major.
你将会战斗
You will fight.
我会努力的, 不过要知道我们所面对的
以及获胜的可能性...
I'll try, but knowing what
we're up against, and the odds...
瞧,  如果你能够请求Athar考虑一下
我们也是她的子民, 我会非常感激的
Look I'd appreciate it if you would ask
Athar to consider that we are her people.
即便我们来自很远的地方, 我们都是相同的
Even though we come from
very far away, we're the same.
我们都是人类, 这就是说我们不是陌生人
We're human, which means we're not strangers.
我们是一家人
We're family.
傍晚的微风
Evening breeze.
我希望这是 Athar 的某种暗示
I was kind of hoping
it was a sign from Athar.
你的话非常有说服力, Sheppard 少校
Your words are most
compelling, Major Sheppard.
谢谢
Thank you.
我希望能够说服
I was going for compelling.
你真的认为我们是一家人?
Do you truly believe we are family?
我们是
We are.
我可以证明给你看
I can prove it to you.
怎么证明?
How?
回到亚特兰蒂斯
Come back to Atlantis.
看我们真正是谁
See who we really are.
一旦 Athar 了解我们更多...
Once Athar learns more about us...
这可以接受
this is acceptable.
是么?
It is?
Chaya, 求你了, 你不能离开
Chaya, please, you cannot leave.
Athar 永远和我们在一起
无论我们在哪里, Zarah.
Athar is with us always,
no matter where we are, Zarah.
我明白了
I understand.
我准备好了
I am ready.
欢迎来到亚特兰蒂斯
Welcome to Atlantis.
谢谢
Thank you.
希望你不要介意
不过我们的医生确实需要对所有外星成员
I hope you don't mind, but our
doctors do require a medical exam
以及我们的访问者
of all off-planet team members
进行医学检查
不过在那之后, 你就可以四处参观一下了
and our visitors, but after that,
perhaps you'd like a full tour.
我会喜欢的
I would love that.
Sheppard 少校已经同意这样做了
Major Sheppard has
already promised to do so.
当然他会的
Of course he has.
当然我会
Of course I have.
请随我到医务室...
Please, if you'll
follow me to the infirmary...
也许我应该跟着
如果你有什么问题的话
maybe I should tag along,
in case you have any questions..
我想我已经搞定了, Rodney.
I think I've got a handle, Rodney.
有很多系统你完全...
There are a lot of systems you know absolutely...
都了解了
Got it covered.
好吧
Fine.
不要动
Hold still.
只要一会儿
Just a minute more.
好了, 亲爱的, 看起来里面的你跟外面一样可爱
Well, my dear, it seems you're just as
lovely on the inside as you are on the out.
如果健康是美丽的同义词
If health is synonymous with beauty.
你可以起来了
You can get up now.
这个设备是如何
How does this device
按照你说的去做的?
do what you say it does?
它建立你身体内部组织的图像
它们都是非常完美的图像
It creates images of the tissues inside
your body, and they are picture-perfect.
这些机器是从你们的星球上带来的么?
Did you bring these
machines back from your world?
有些是
Some.
其他的则是亚特兰蒂斯人的技术
我们只是知道怎么使用, 还有一些...
Others are atlantean technology that
we've figured out how to use, and a few...
嗯, 我甚至根本不知道它们是做什么的
well, I haven't the vaguest idea what they do.
希望某天我能够和他们当中的某个会会面
Hopefully one day I'll have a chance to meet one.
我亲自去问问他们
I'll ask them myself.
你知道他们发生了什么?
Do you know what happened to them?
嗯, 在和幽灵的战争之后
有一些回到了地球
Well, some returned to Earth
after the war with the Wraith.
这就是我们知道的了
不过我们还知道他们当中有些人升天了
That much we know, but we also
know that some of them ascended.
升天?
Ascended?
进入一个更高的层次
在那里他们仅仅以能量的形式存在
To a higher plane,
where they exist only as energy.
你那个星球中的所有人都跟你一样健康么?
Are all the people of
your world as healthy as you?
是的
Yes.
没有疾病?
No disease, ailments?
从来没有人摔断腿?
No one ever breaks a leg?
这种事情很少
不过我的人民很快就会痊愈了
Such things are rare,
but my people heal quite rapidly.
真的?
Really?
我们完了么?
Are we done?
完了么?
Are we?
我见过的最健康的病人了
Healthiest patient I've ever had.
你可以走了, 亲爱的
Off you go, love.
情况到底怎样?
Where are we at?
好吧, 要么她知道武器在哪里
却故意在玩弄我们
Well, either she knows where
the weapon is and she's playing us,
要么她确实不知道
不管是哪种情况, 我们都在浪费时间
or else she has no idea,
in which case, we are wasting our time.
那么你的建议是?
So what do you suggest?
派另外一对人乘飞船过去
扫描那个行星上的能量信号
Take another team back in the jumper,
scan the planet for energy signatures.
Chaya的人民不会察觉我们在轨道上所做的事情
Chaya's people won't have a
clue what we're doing from orbit,
除非他们已经有了发达的科技
只是假装出来不是这样
unless they're a technically advanced
race that are pretending not to be,
这在以前也发生过
which has happened before.
你找到什么不正常的东西了么?
Did you find anything abnormal?
我的意思是, 可以证明比他们声称的更发达的东西?
I mean, something that would suggest they
are more advanced than they claim to be?
没有, 他们的技术要么是可怜的后进
要么就是超乎寻常的先进
No, They're either pathetically pretechnological
or brilliantly post-technological.
而且那肯定不会是一个自然现象?
And there's no way this
could be a natural phenomenon?
非常恰当的时机, 非常合适的方向
那股能量爆发刚好只影响了幽灵的飞船
A perfectly timed, directional energy burst
that only affected the Wraith ships?
- 就是说不会是了?
- 不可能是
- That's a no?
- That's a no.
Weir 博士,  我已经有了结果了
Dr. Weir,  I have those results.
谢谢你, Carson. 我们正过来
Thank you, Carson. We're on our way.
你们一共有多少人?
How many of you are there?
把所有在大陆的人都算在内
Counting all the athosians on the mainland,
大概有两百人
you might get a couple of hundred,
住在一个非常大, 而且空旷的城市中
which leaves a very large, empty city.
现在, 我们只住在一个区域
因为我们的能量无法分散到更多的区域
Right now, we're living in one section, because we
don't have the power to spread out more than that.
你认为这里怎么样?
What do you think so far?
我想这非常令人惊奇
I think it's wondrous...
不过最终, 这都是 Athar 的结果
but ultimately, the decision is up to Athar.
你并不是信徒, 是么?
You're not a believer, are you?
瞧, Chaya...
Look, Chaya...
我尊重你所信仰的
I respect that you believe.
瞧, 我无法同 Athar 对话
Look, I can't talk to Athar,
我只能跟你谈谈, 我想问你
如果鞋穿在另一只脚上会怎么样呢?
I can only talk to you, so let me ask you this
what if the shoe was on the other foot?
如果是你的人民处于危难之中
而我们又可以提供帮助呢?
What if your people were in trouble
and we could help you?
难道你也只是回答不么?
Would you just take no for an answer?
你们整日处于幽灵的阴影之下, 肯定活得非常艰难
It must have been very hard to live your
entire life under the shadow of the Wraith.
不要误解我的意思
Don't misunderstand me.
Teyla 和她的人民很早就认识幽灵了
Teyla and her people have
known the Wraith forever,
不过我们在这里是新人
我的意思是, 我们刚刚才到这里
but when I say we're new,
I mean we just got here.
我们是从另外一个星系来的
一个叫做地球的行星
We're from another galaxy.
A planet called Earth.
地球?
Earth?
非常遥远
It's very far away.
知道那些你在夜空中看到的那些星团么?
You know those clusters of
stars you see in the night sky?
其中的某些被称作星系
Some of them are called galaxies,
他们比这些星星离你更远
and they're even further
away from you than the stars.
地球就在其中的一个星系当中
Earth is in one of those galaxies.
你们通过星际之门来到这里
You came through the Stargate.
对
That's right.
那你们为什么不能就那样回去?
And can you not simply return?
好吧,  没那么简单
Well, not simply.
我们跨进它就知道这可能是一个单程旅行
We knew going into it that it was
probably going to be a one-way trip,
不过我们认为我们在这里所发现的值得去冒那个险
but we thought what we would
find here would be worth the risk.
是这样么?
And is it?
目前为止是
So far.
等到幽灵出现的时候再问我吧
Ask me again when the Wraith show up.
血液检查显示没有病毒, 细菌以及寄生虫感染
Blood work shows no viral,
bacterial, or parasitic infections.
核磁共振显示没有肿瘤和癌症
没有任何类型的心脏疾病
Mri reveals no tumors or cancers,
no heart defects of any kind.
血压130  70,
胆固醇 107.
Blood pressure 130 over 70,
total cholesterol 107.
她非常健康
She's in perfect health.
我为她感到高兴
I'm happy for her.
你为什么让我们看这些?
Why did we need to see this?
因为, 博士
她实在是太健康了
Because, doctor,
she's too healthy.
这是什么意思?
What does that mean?
没有任何疾病以及先天不足的迹象
There's no trace of any
diseases or congenital conditions
而那在她们哪种技术水平的社会应该很常见
that you typically find in
pretechnological societies.
没有佝偻病, 没有真菌...
No rickets, no fungi, stds...
完美的健康?
perfect health?
是的, 根据她所告诉我的
这在她的人民当中非常平常
Aye, and from what she told me,
this may be the norm among her people.
但是她是人类?
But she is human?
噢, 毫无疑问
Oh, without a doubt.
那么这又怎么可能?
So how is that possible?
我也无法解释
除非我亲自去那个星球看看
I can't say that for certain
without visiting the planet myself,
如果这些数据是准确的
那么居住在Proculis的人民
but if this data is accurate,
then people on Proculis
可以健康的生活很长很长的时间
live in optimal health for a
very, very long time.
- 你让这听起来好像是...
- 天堂?
- You make it sound like some sort of a...
- paradise?
是的, 因为它就是
Aye, because it is.
这就是问题, 因为...
And that's a problem because...
因为人类的生命, 非常简单
Weir博士, 比这要脆弱得多
because human life, quite simply,
dr. Weir, is more fragile than that.
我不管我们是在那个星系
I don't care what galaxy we're in.
这是不自然的
It's unnatural.
海上上的空气真是令人爽快啊
The ocean air is so invigorating.
这里多的是
Plenty of that here.
大多数行星的海洋
Most of the planet's ocean.
确实有足够的陆地来安顿那些难民么
Well surely there's enough
land to resettle the refugees.
当然
Well, there is.
我们只是不能保证他们的安全
We just can't guarantee their safety.
即使你们可以控制所有这些?
Even though you control all of this?
如果我说过我们可以控制所有这些, 那么我是在撒谎
I'd be lying if I said we controlled it all.
这个地方在很多方面超越了我们的能力
This place is so far beyond us in so many ways.
比如, 亚特兰蒂斯有一个可以抵挡任何东西的防护罩
For example, Atlantis does have a
shield that can withstand anything
可以把幽灵抵挡在外
不过我们没有办法给它提供能量
the Wraith could throw at us,
but we have no way of powering it up.
这里已经有太多的难民了
我们不能冒险接收更多
We can't risk taking in any
more refugees than we already have.
跟我来
Come with me.
Sheppard 少校...
Major Sheppard...
我更愿意你叫我John.
I'd prefer you call me John.
John...
你们又是怎么跟幽灵结仇的呢?
how did you make enemies of the Wraith?
那都是我的错
That was my fault.
你的错?
Yours?
我在试图拯救那些他们抓去的人时
把它们给唤醒了
I basically woke them up trying to
rescue some people they'd captured.
它们对那一点也不友好
They didn't take too kindly to that.
但是你救出了你的人?
But you saved your people?
大部分
Most of them.
你怎么确信他们一定会回来?
And that is how you know
for sure they're coming back?
是的, 不过我们当时并不知道
Yeah, we just don't know when.
主控制台, 环境支持系统, 通信系统
Main control console, environmental
support systems, communications,
还有这个, 这是, 嗯...
and this, this is, uh...
抱歉, 少校
我们还完全不知道这是...
Sorry, Major.
We haven't the faintest idea what it...
这是我们在城市另外一个区域找到的设备
this is a new piece of equipment
we found in another section of the city.
它还没有被初始化过
It hadn't yet been initialized.
那么你说她拥有...
So you're saying she has...
她拥有那个基金
she has the gene.
这是我干的么?
Then I did this?
这个机器是做什么的?
What does the machine do?
无论如何, 现在, 我们还不知道,
We don't know. Not yet, anyway.
亚特兰蒂斯人做这些东西确实非常出色
The Atlanteans were good at lots of things,
不过写说明书除外
but writing instruction
manuals wasn't one of them.
我们可能需要结束参观了
We should probably wrap this tour up.
我知道Weir博士现在肯定很想见到你
I know dr. Weir is anxious to talk to you.
在那以后我还能看到你么?
Will I see you afterwards?
你会一直看到我
And during.
我们所建议的是你们能否出租一些土地
What we are proposing
is a kind of land lease,
这样受到幽灵袭击
in which refugees rendered homeless
而无家可归的人们
就可以在Proculis重新安顿了
by the Wraith could resettle on Proculis.
作为回报, 我们会提供服务和知识
In return, we can offer
you services and knowledge
这些可以帮助你的人民
which would be of benefit to your people.
例如?
Such as?
好吧, 你已经看到了我们这里所拥有的技术
Well, you've seen the sort
of technology we possess here.
我们可以帮助你们步入一个更加工业化的社会
We could help you down a path
to a more industrialized society,
而且这样的发展步伐仍然会保持
你那个星球的生态平行
but at a pace that will maintain
your planet's ecological balance.
你的科学知识非常打动人
Weir 博士, 不过我们并不需要它
Your scientific knowledge is impressive,
dr. Weir, but we have no need of it.
Athar 已经提供给我们所有我们想要的了
Athar provides us with everything we require.
嗯, 食物并不会自动在餐桌上出现
Well, food just doesn't
show up on the dinner table.
你们的庄稼都是靠你们自己种出来的?
You do plant all your own crops?
是的, 当然
Of course we do.
我们可以教你们一些方法来提高你们作物的产量
We can show you ways
to increase your crop yields.
我们种的食物已经足够我们生存了
We grow all the food we need to live.
再多一点就是暴食了
Anything else would be gluttony.
那么, 建筑材料
Building materials, then.
我们已经有非常充裕的木料和铁矿石了
We have abundant timber and iron ore
to forge what little metal we need.
Athar 实在是太仁慈了
Athar is kind.
一定会有什么的
There must be something.
我的人民人为价值最高的是精神上的知识
What my people value
most is spiritual knowledge.
你们的文明可以在那方面回报些什么?
What can your culture provide in that regard?
地球上的人们不会分享
单一的精神信仰
Earth's people don't share
a single spiritual belief.
我们包含了很多信仰和哲学
We embrace a number of
different religions and philosophies...
基督教, 佛教
Christianity, Buddhism,
犹太教, 伊斯兰教...
Judaism, Islam...
印度教
Hinduism.
Kwanzaa...
有意思
Interesting.
跟我讲讲它们
Tell me about them.
所有的?
All of them?
是的, 它们听起来非常迷人
Yes. They sound fascinating.
好吧,  我还没有能力来讨论
地球上所有的宗教
Well, I am hardly competent
to discuss all of Earth's religions,
不过我可以提供给你一些资源
but I can offer you some resources.
通过很简单的训练
你就可以完全访问我们的历史数据库了
With very little training, you could have
complete access to our historical database.
那太好了
That would be wonderful.
你让它工作起来了?
You got it working?
是的
Yeah.
那好, 我们知道它是做什么的么?
Well, do we know what it does?
它看起来好像是一个内外生物传感器阵列
It would appear to be an
internal-external biometric sensor array.
哦, 现在, sadly, 我明白了
See, now, sadly, I understood that.
他们星期六晚上到哪里去了?
Where did all those saturday nights go?
这些看起来像是亚特兰蒂斯中
所有人的生物标识
These seem to be the
biosignatures of everyone in Atlantis.
你怎么知道?
我从这些杂乱无章的东西中完全找不出头绪
How can you tell? I can't make
heads or tails out of that mess.
我以前的工作是解码古人的对数
I've been working on
deciphering the ancient logarithms.
我想这个是设计用来作为早期预警系统的
I suspect this was designed
primarily as an early warning system,
假如有异族侵入, 就像幽灵, 就发出信号
to signal any alien presence
in the city, like the Wraith.
你刚才说当我们的访问者
触摸到它的时候, 它就被激活了?
And you're saying that it
activated when our visitor touched it?
这表示她一定有古人的基因
Which must mean she has the ancient gene.
或者它已经被初始化过了
然后只要检测到她就会被激活
Or it was initialized already and only
activated because it was detecting her.
我的意思是,  它可能是某种异族
I mean, she could be some kind of an alien,
这个东西相对我们所能破译的
了解她更多
and this thing knows more about
her than we've been able to decipher.
必须有人去盯住她
Someone should be keeping an eye on her.
有 Sheppard 少校在
Major Sheppard is.
哦, 我想是的
Oh, I'm sure he is.
不过不完全是你所想的原因
Not entirely for the reasons you think.
Weir 博士要求他这么做
Dr. Weir asked him to.
哦, 我想他一定会的
Oh, I'm sure she did.
Weir 博士希望我
确保让Chaya 看到一切
Dr. Weir wanted me to make
sure Chaya saw everything.
一切?
Everything?
嗯, 不是一切, 一切
Well, not everything, everything.
Chaya 提到她想看到城市夜晚最美丽的景色
Chaya mentioned she wanted to
see the best view of the city at night,
我想应该是在西南塔的顶上
不过考虑到有一段很长的路要走
which I think is atop the southwest pier,
and since it's such a long walk,
我想我应该带上一些食品
I thought I'd bring along a few provisions.
继续我们谈判的努力
Continuing our efforts to secure a treaty.
很对
Exactly.
作为我们的外交官
As our ambassador.
我是外交官, 那么她就是...
I am an ambassador, and she is a...
大使
diplomat.
在深夜...野餐上?
On a late-night...picnic?
是的
Yes.
我知道那是作为亚特兰蒂斯的最高军事指挥官
I know that as ranking
military officer here in Atlantis
而且你感觉担负的责任很重
that you feel a heavy burden of responsibility,
不过你...
but you...
也要考虑一下别人是怎么想的
are allowed to have feelings for others.
噢.  不, 这只是...
Oh. No, this is a...
这只是一个大使级的外交上的野餐
this is an ambassadorial,
diplomatic picnic outing.
除了...
Without...
不必在每个人面前证明他们自己的身份
having to justify them to anyone.
晚安, 少校
Good night, Major.
晚安, Teyla.
Good night, Teyla.
你要把她送回去?
You want to send her back?
我所知道的全部就是
现在的她是假装出来的, 并不是真正的她
All I know is she's not who
she's pretending to be.
你知道这因为...
And you know this because...
怎么, 我就不能有直觉了?
what, I'm not allowed to have intuition?
你? 不
You? No.
我已经让Sheppard少校注意她了
I asked Major Sheppard
to keep an eye on her.
这就好像是让狐狸去看家
Which is like asking the
fox to guard the henhouse.
什么?
What?
好吧, 你看, 生物学上的区别不是非常显著, Elizabeth.
Well, look, the biometric
differential is not insignificant, Elizabeth.
我想说的是...
What I'm saying is...
那个女人引起了异族警报
the woman set off an alien alarm.
噢, 这个你也不是很确信
Come on, you don't know that for certain.
现在, grodin 说你也不知道
那个设备的工作机制
Now, grodin says you are nowhere close to
understanding what the nature of that device is.
有太多的未知变数
那里有能量武器
There are too many unknown variables.
There's the energy weapon,
他们声称从来没有见过幽灵...
the fact that they claim never
to have seen the Wraith...
还有她那完全合乎规范的健康
what about the fact that she's
essentially a textbook case of healthy?
是的, 这都很神秘
不过这又能证明什么呢?
All very mysterious, yes,
but what does it prove?
那就是我们要给她一张单程票, 让她回家
That we should give her
a one-way ticket back home.
看起来她身上确实有些事情非常...
There is obviously something very...
与众不同, 是的, 不过这些都不足以证明
她是一个有威胁的人物
different about her, yes, but that
doesn't necessarily make her a threat.
这同时也不合常理
It doesn't rule it out, either.
那么, 目前,  我想我们通过谈判可以获得的
Then, for the moment,
I think what we could gain
已经值得冒险让她留在这里
by securing a treaty is worth
the risk of her being here.
好吧
Fine.
这个味道好极了
This is delicious.
嗯, 尽情享受吧
因为那是我们的最后一个了
Well, enjoy it while you can,
because that's the last of what we have.
那我真是太荣幸了
Then I am honored.
要是 McKay 发现了, 他会杀了我的
When McKay finds out,
he's going to kill me.
Athar 会拯救你的
Athar will save you.
噢, 好啊
Oh, good.
如此令人惊奇的东西
Such wondrous things.
这么多种食物, 除了不停的吃
我再也想不起去做别的事情了
I can't imagine wanting to do anything but
eat all the time with such a variety of foods.
好吧, 那就让我们尽情地投入吧
Well, we manage to pull
ourselves away somehow.
我已经知道了很多关于地球的事情
I've been learning much about Earth.
Weir 博士已经带我去见识你的信息机器了
Dr. Weir has gotten me
on your information machines.
Elizabeth已经让你去操作计算机了, 嗯?
Elizabeth's got you on
a computer already, huh?
我为你们那么多的宗教而着迷
I'm fascinated by your many religions.
如此多的信仰
So many beliefs.
如此多的哲学
So many philosophies.
是的, 我们接受其中的某些
Yeah, we've got a few of those.
同时还有很多反对的信仰
So many contradictory faiths.
是的, 这有点混乱
Yeah, it's a bit of a mess.
再来一点?
More?
好的
Yes, please.
我们通过贸易交换葡萄
We traded for grapes.
那些athosians人, Teyla的人民
The athosians, Teyla's people,
他们在大陆种植这些
they make this on the mainland.
我对你说的有些话不是完全诚实的
I wasn't completely truthful
with you about something.
在Proculis, 当我告诉你我从未感觉到孤独的时候...
On Proculis, when I told
you I did not feel lonely...
来到这里, 跟你在一起...
coming here and being with you...
提醒我, 不再孤单的感觉是什么样的
it reminded me what it
was like not to be alone.
什么?
What?
呵呵, 我的意思是, 没有什么
Well, I mean, nothing.
只是...
It's just that...
这是我第一次在外星球和一个女人
如此的罗曼蒂克
this is the first time I've been in a romantic
situation with a woman from another planet,
这让我觉得有点...
and it just strikes me as really,...
不好?
wrong?
不. 天哪, 不是
No. God, no.
只是... 只是...
Just... just...
好笑
funny.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我只是在想
I just thought
我要, 嗯...
that I would, uh...
你自己说的...
you said it yourself...
我们都是人类
we're both human.
是的, 我们是的, 我非常高兴你
没有说"家人", 要不然我就得离开了
Yes, we are, and I'm really glad you
didn't say "family" otherwise I'd have to leave.
不要
Don't.
我哪也不去
I'm not going anywhere.
少校
Major.
Rodney.
在做什么, 搞得这么晚 ?
What are you doing up so late?
我只是, 嗯...
I was just, uh...
我睡不着, 所以我回到
控制室做点小研究
I couldn't sleep, so I was going back up
to the control room to do a little research.
你呢?
What about you?
哦, 不, 谢谢了
Oh, no thanks.
不, 我的意思是, 你做什么搞得这么晚?
No, I mean, what were you doing up so late?
我总是搞得很晚, rodney.
I'm always up late, rodney.
一点警告...
A word of caution...
kirk上尉的例行公事般的回答很有问题
言语简短, 更不用说精神上的疑点了
the whole captain kirk routine is problematic,
to say the least, let alone morally dubious.
什么例行公事?
What routine?
罗曼史, 外来的女祭司
The romancing, the alien priestess.
你真是像是回到了1967年
It's very 1967 of you.
事实上, 我很奇怪...
Actually, I'm surprised...
我做的这些跟你有什么关系...
if and when anything I do
becomes your business...
这跟我有关, 少校,  当那个外来的女人
并不像她自己所讲述的那样时
it becomes my business, major, when an alien
woman who is clearly not who she claims to be
我们的最高指挥官却在抱着她的小指
has the ranking military officer
wrapped around her little finger.
不要讲这些, McKay.
Don't go there, McKay.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我知道我平常不是很敏感
I know I'm not normally
mr. Sensitive, but you've got to
不过在我讲某些确实跟她有关的事情时
我希望你能够相信我
believe me when I say
there is something about her.
我知道这是不可捉摸的, 不过我可以感觉得到...
I know it's intangible, but I can feel it...
我说了, 不要讲了
I said, don't go there.
这只是时间的问题
我会证明给你看的, 少校
It's just a matter of time
before I prove it, Major.
我只是建议在同时, 你管好你的...
I'm just recommending that in
the meantime, you keep your...
你昨晚睡着了么?
did you sleep last night?
没有. 生物传感器有一些数据
No. This is the data
from the biometric sensors.
我不能说出所有这些信号所代表的意思
不过, 嗯, 看看这个
I can't tell you exactly what all of
these signatures mean, but, uh, look at this,
这是我们, 还有这, 这是她
these are ours, and this, this is hers.
有很大的不同
There's a distinct difference.
她出生在另外一个星系的另外一个星球
She was born on another
planet in another galaxy.
它们跟Teyla 的也不同
They're different from Teyla's too.
这并不意味着...
That doesn't mean...
Elizabeth, 她跟看起来得不一样.
Elizabeth, she's not
what she seems to be.
除了她是一个非常诚实正直的人
我再也感觉不到什么其他的
I sense nothing but a very
honest and spiritual person.
好吧
All right.
有一个方法可以检查出来
there may be a way to find out.
你们今早要跟她进行谈判, 对么?
You're opening negotiations
with her this morning, right?
是的
Yeah.
好吧, 这样, 让我坐在里面
Okay, well, let me sit in.
我会假装是在本本上记笔记
实际上我会扫描她, 检测看是否有异常
I'll pretend to be taking notes on the laptop
when really I'll be scanning her for anomalies.
放射线, E.M. 扫描, 能量信号...
Radiation, E.M. Scans, energy signatures...
这种方法, 除非我疯了, 只能让你我两个人知道
that way, if I am crazy, you and I
are the only ones who need to know.
现在, 这样做有什么坏处么?
Now, what's the harm?
好吧...
All right...
不过一定要小心
but be discreet.
我就是"小心"先生
I'm mr. Discreet.
我同意我所读过的地球上的宗教打动了我
I admit to being impressed by most
of what I've read of Earth's religions.
The torah (《圣经·旧约全书》开头五篇),
the koran ( 伊斯兰教 《古兰经》),
the talmud ( 犹太教法典古代拉比著作的合集
包括《密西拿》和《革马拉》),
the bible...
The torah, the koran,
the talmud, the bible...
它们当中的大多数展示了多种多样的
以及深切的对神的追求
most of them reveal a diverse
and deep desire to grasp the divine.
这么说我们确实有一些可以提供给你们的东西了
So we do have something we can offer you.
不过我同时也读过你们的历史
But I've also been reading about your history.
即便是现在, 在你们的星球上
仍然有战争
Even now, somewhere on
your planet, you are at war.
嗯, 是的, 这是真的
Well, yeah, that's true.
我并没有想向你掩饰这些真相
I made no attempt to
hide that fact from you.
Chaya, 我们并不是完美的
Chaya, we are definitely not perfect.
作为人类, 我发现你们有太多的困扰了
There's a lot about you as
a people that I find disturbing.
难道其他人不是这样?
Can that not be said of any people?
不是
No.
Proculis 中的每一个灵魂都可以远离憎恨和愤怒
Every soul in Proculis is free
from the hatred and the anger
而地球上的人们彼此之间却经常这样
the people from Earth
seem to feel for each other.
噢
Come on.
我们没有那么糟糕
We're not all that bad.
你是知道的
You know that.
我知道
I do.
我们并没有谈论地球上的人们
We're not talking about
the people on Earth.
我是在谈论我的探险队的每个成员
在这里, 亚特兰蒂斯
I'm talking about every member
of my expedition team here, in Atlantis,
以及自从我们到这里之后碰到的朋友
就像, Teyla的人民
and I'm talking about the friends we've
met since coming here, like Teyla's people.
那也包括你, 你自己也包括在内, Weir 博士
There are some among you,
yourself included, Dr. Weir
我知道 Athar 会张开双臂欢迎...
that I know Athar would
welcome with open arms...
不过是其他人
but there are others.
我已经挑选了这个探险队中的每个人
I hand-picked every
member of this expedition,
我知道 Teyla 对她自己的人民很有信心
and I know Teyla feels as
confident about her own people.
我知道
I'm sure.
在今天结束之前
这只是一个信任的问题
At the end of the day,
this is a matter of trust.
是的
Yes.
是这样,  Weir 博士
It is, dr. Weir.
你扫描到一些东西没有,  McKay博士?
Have your scans found
anything yet, Dr. McKay?
事实上...
Actually...
没有
no.
这到底是什么?
What the hell is this?
我很抱歉, 少校
I'm sorry, Major.
我们有理由调查清楚...
There was cause for
legitimate concern as to...
我跟我声称的是否相同
whether I was or not who I claimed to be.
我很抱歉, Chaya.
I'm sorry, Chaya.
我真诚地希望这没有伤害你
I honestly felt it would do no harm.
不要道歉了, Elizabeth.
Stop apologizing, Elizabeth.
她是怎么知道的?
How did she know?
McKay...
她是一个古人, 少校.
she's an ancient, Major.
她是什么?
She's what?
我是对的, 是么?
I'm right, aren't I?
完美的健康, 那个能量武器
The perfect health, the energy weapon,
她所具有的基因...
the fact that she has the gene...
在逻辑上只有一个解释
it's the only logical explanation.
你到底在说些什么?
What the hell are you talking about?
我只是不明白这种行为
I just don't understand the act.
我的意思是, 你要知道我们实在不惜一切代价的
同你们交谈, 向你们学习
I mean, you must know we'd give just about
anything to talk to you, to learn from you.
我的意思是, 到底是什么?
I mean, what is it?
你要... 检查我们什么?
What, are you... checking us out?
我渴望来到亚特兰蒂斯
I see that in my desire to come to Atlantis,
你们已经把我揭示得太多了
I have revealed too much of myself.
他是对的?
He's right?
我说对了?
I'm right?
我就是你们所称作的"古人"...
I am what you call an "Ancient"...
而且事实上我也根本不能
向你们提供避难所...
and it is also true that I can
never offer your people sanctuary...
不过我来这里的原因, 你们解释错了.
but you are wrong as to why I came here.
你为什么来这里?
Why did you come here?
你, John.
You, John.
我?
Me?
我孤独的生活了那么长时间
这时你邀请我来到亚特兰蒂斯, 我...
I have lived in solitude for so long that
when you asked me to come to Atlantis, I...
噢, 我的天哪, 他是Kirk.
oh, my god, he is Kirk.
这么说从来不是为了 ...
So this was never about, ...
我们能够独自在这里呆会么?
could we just have a
moment to ourselves here?
不行
No.
没关系
That's all right.
我已经在这里呆得够长了
I've stayed here long enough.
来吧, Chaya.
Come on, Chaya.
你和你的人民是我们来这里的首要原因
You and your people were the
reason we came here in the first place.
我不能... 我不能...
I can't... I can't...
不
no.
这到底是什么?
What the hell was that?
它们来了
They're coming for them.
我不应该丢下他们
I should have never left them.
发生什么了?
What's going on?
我很抱歉, John.
I'm sorry, John.
我要驾一艘飞船回到Proculis.
I'm taking a jumper back to Proculis.
刚刚发生了什么?
What just happened?
要想可以找出原因我们只有一种办法
There's only one way to find out.
去吧
Go.
少校, 你可知道那边会是什么情况?
Major, are you sure you
know what you're flying into?
我敢确信幽灵正在袭击Chaya 的人民
I have a pretty good idea the
Wraith are attacking Chaya's people.
只有一艘船, 你别指望能打败它们!
You can't hope to
defend them with one ship!
我想我也没有必要
I don't think I'll have to.
你来这里做什么?
What are you doing here?
我来帮你
I'm here to help you.
帮我?
Help me?
保护你的人民
To defend your people.
离开
Leave.
我会处理的
I will take care of this.
是 "Chaya" 么...
Is it "Chaya"...
或者是 "Athar"?
我只是很好奇
or "Athar"?
I'm just curious.
当我是一个凡人时, 我住在这里
When I was mortal, I lived here.
这是我的家
This was my home.
当我们当中那些你们称之为古人的升天后
When those of us who
you call the ancients ascended,
我们本应该抛弃我们的人类情节
we were supposed to
leave behind us all human ties.
我们当中某些人发现这太困难了
Some of us found that difficult.
所以你无法眼看着你的人民
So you couldn't
stand by and watch your people
被幽灵清洗
而无动于衷
getting wiped out by the Wraith.
当它们可怕的舰队接近时
我的心里就会非常不安
When their terrible fleet approached,
I lashed out with my mind
只有一个念头, 把它们全部都消灭
and with a single thought,
destroyed them all.
我同类中的其他人并不赞同这种干涉
The others of my kind did not
approve of such interference
对有形事物的干涉
于是我就被放逐
with corporeal matters,
and so I was exiled.
对我的惩罚就是无终止的保卫这个星球
My punishment was the
unending protection of this world.
那究竟为什么要装扮成人类?
Why pretend to be human at all?
这样, 日积月累
我就可以走到人民中去
So that, time to time,
I may walk among the people,
作为仁慈友好的灵魂而被它们所接受
know them as the good and kind souls they are.
几千年来
我来到又离开了那些村庄
For thousands of years,
I have come and gone to the villages,
不过呆得都很短, 一直没有附上任何人...
never staying too long
to get attached to anyone...
直道我遇见了你
until I met you.
这些年来, 我从来没有对以前所作的选择后悔过...
I have never regretted the
choice I made all of these years...
直到现在
until now.
我被允许保卫我的人民
不过仅限于我的人民
I am permitted to safeguard
my people, but my people only.
这就是对我的惩罚
This is my punishment.
这就是它为什么被称之为惩罚
This is what makes it punishment.
如果你们的人来到这里寻求我的保护
If your people came
here for my protection,
其他人就会阻止我
the others would stop me.
你明白了么?
Do you understand?
我无法帮助你们的人
I can never help your people.
我想我不能如此轻松的走开
I'm not sure I'm willing
to walk away that easily,
我也并不想在这里谈论个人问题
and I'm not just talking personally here,
虽然这已经成为了事实...
although that's definitely part of it...
我们仍然有很多东西可以向你们学习
there is so much more
we can learn from you.
我不能, John.
I can't, John.
其他人不会同意的
The others won't allow it.
这只是...
That's just...
他们最高的法则, 决不干涉
it is their highest law to never interfere.
我被限制在这些法则中了
尽管我也很想帮助你
I am bound by those laws,
however much I wish to help you.
如此, 那么, 我们不能...
So, uh, we can never...
我不能离开
I can never leave.
好吧, 我可以到这里来看你
Well, I could come and visit.
现在我正在挑逗一个其他的物种
Now I'm flirting with
somebody from another species.
我们的差别并没有你所想象的那么大
We're not as different as you think.
噢, 我想我们的差别比你想的要大
Oh, I think we're more
different than you think.
我可以展示给你看
I can show you.
展示给我看?
Show me?
通过彼此之间的分享
By sharing each other.
我们会像其他人一样, 相互了解对方
We will know each other
as well as anyone ever can.
好吧
Okay.
午夜之前我要把车送回去, 虽然
I've got to get the car
back by midnight, though.
这只需要花一点时间
This will only take a few moments.
闭上你的眼睛
Just close your eyes.
这可真是酷阿...
This is cool...